at least some of the stuff that I'm that
I'm thinking of right now that I'm you
know you can see results I'm holding
myself back he's like his blood pressure
is 180 over 30. you know like yeah and
so oh man my heart's gonna explode Joel
[Music]
thank you
all right we're rolling I just I just
feel like somebody stabbed me in the
heart with a knife man oh yeah what what
did you just get dudes or something what
happened I I just got a message on one
of my reports for the live hacking event
that's like hey there's like this
mitigating factor to your most impactful
report and it just like and it just hit
right before the Pod too so I'm like oh
so now I'm just oh I can't stop thinking
about like how am I gonna bypass that
how am I going to bypass that but you
know it happens it's the life of a bug
Bounty Hunter yeah yeah man that's rough
that that sucks I hate it when that
happens we should maybe have a new
policy that you shouldn't check your
email but right before the Pod yeah
that's a good idea yeah I I gotta I
don't know man I I ought to I get the
push notifications on my phone obviously
for my email and then as soon as I see
it's like from hacker one related stuff
it's like crack like I gotta open that
[__] right away you know and and uh but
sometimes it it it comes comes across
pretty hard and uh man my fickle heart
yeah I had one of those yesterday
morning too I was I was like just waking
up I was going through my inbox and I
was like oh hey they finally updated the
report over from that I reported before
the weekend I go on a check and uh
they're like oh uh actually uh this is
informative I
hate it still happens still happens man
actually you know I don't know what's up
with this event and I'm glad my my sort
of QA process it but I've actually had
two or three false positives this event
that I was getting ready to submit and I
was like wait maybe I should just run
through this again and then I run
through it again and it's you know I got
something messed up and it's like ah it
just takes the wind out of you so bad I
hate that yeah we had that happen a
couple times as well where it's like
things were behaving like super weird
and we're like yeah maybe this is like a
bug we should probably report it let's
just double check it and like run it
through it just doesn't doesn't work
again and yeah so are you working with
someone for this event uh I'm working
with a bunch of different people in just
like little different things just
collabing around yeah it's just like
little bugs like if they have like one
thing that they want to like work on
we'll like go we'll jam on that and then
like I'll go and I'll message them by
myself and then I'll hop over to
somebody else and yeah nice nice yeah I
I I've got I think I think we're like
five or six days into the event now and
I've got like four or five bugs and and
I hope this impactful one that I kind of
you know rabbit hold on I hope I can
figure it out because if I I can't
that's gonna be that's gonna be painful
for sure but I'm I'm so a little bit
slower than usual but the scope for this
event is a little bit tricky so I'm I'm
happy with it yeah yeah it's really
interesting I was just commenting on
somebody else that uh
like these big events are are fun but
also like not as fun I think just
because for one like there's so much
scope that it's almost hard to like
figure out what you should be looking at
and not trying to optimize and then
usually the larger events have more
hackers which is more intimidating
there's more reports like right now I
won't say who but like one of the one of
the targets there's two Targets one of
the targets has like
150 reports or something already the
other one has like 80. and like one
person alone has like 70 reports on one
of the targets so it's like yeah it's
kind of crazy yeah there's like a lot a
lot so for me like the Imposter syndrome
and they're like oh man I'm just gonna
dupe on everything that's like huge
right now but uh you gotta like figure
out ways to navigate through that yeah
it's events like these where you gotta
really stick to the tips that you preach
on the Pod like I come on the Pod and
I'm like really you know you just gotta
stay in your lane pick your target you
know pone it just go for it don't worry
about but then when you get in the
situation applying it is so much
different you know yeah and so I I
definitely feel that but the other thing
about these bigger live hacking events
is that
um you know there's so much scope and in
the beginning you can't really do due
diligence on everything to see like all
right this is where I should you know go
hack because it takes too much time so
it for this for this event there's
probably
there's probably 15 applications that I
could spend the whole event on in in
scope for this for this event right and
so really you just got to pick your one
and you got to stick to it and you got
to do it right
but it's also kind of a crap shoot then
because you you could just pick the
wrong app you know the app that's just
not as vulnerable and and you know you
do your best to do your due diligence at
the beginning but you know that's just
kind of how the cards lie sometimes
um so I'm I'm having fun with my app and
as long as I make my my little you know
nut that I need for the month or
whatever then I think it'll be good yeah
yeah that's awesome yeah I had a very
similar experience where like
before the event started before the
kickoff calls I was like okay I'm gonna
focus on this thing like specifically
I'm just gonna spend all the time like
hacking this one thing and I'm gonna
find some sick bugs gonna take me some
time then like two days in I was already
hacking the other targets
man like I need to like go hack this
other stuff like ugh I'm not finding
what I want here I need to like switch
it up like yeah this is this is one of
the reasons I think I enjoyed our last
our last little collab that we did
together over the previous life hacking
event because I think uh I think one of
my things is I will actually stick to
the Target that I commit to like and and
I just I won't get derailed won't go
look at anything else I'll just stick to
it and I think if I and I think you have
the capability to jump around from
different Target to Target and still
find bugs but I think if I can just
direct you you know and just like no
Joel we're gonna focus on this like this
is the thing like let's do it right now
then I think we had some really cool
results and stuff that's true I've been
told this in other aspects of my life as
well that it's like I'm like a car
that's like speeding forwards but I have
like really bad turning and so like if
somebody could just like steer it in the
right direction it's just like Full
Speed Ahead but yeah keeping keeping
keeping the analogy though you know you
are moving quicker than most people are
though so I think I think it works for
you you know you still get where you're
going you know even if you're not taking
the most efficient path yeah yeah well
I'll get there in the end you know yeah
cool for sure all right let's Dive In
some news yeah yeah what's on the first
step on the docket okay so I was
scrolling through Twitter this morning I
literally like I woke up I wake up at
like crazy early it's like five o'clock
in the morning I'm like open Twitter
and like I have this notification it
says like new tweet from infosec Au oh
man here we go and like for the record I
love shoves I don't have tweet
notifications turned on which means that
this is like a popular enough tweet that
I got sent to me okay like by Twitter
and uh I open it up and it's like oh
yeah I was working on this like crazy
research with with CLC and Brett science
and Rhys Elmore and uh yeah here's a
blog post and I like open it up and it's
like hacking like root TLD servers
Okay cool so they hacked the internet
got it they did it again
um it's so funny you say that because
that's literally the exact same thing
that happened to me like I I mean it's
minus the whole waking up at you know
crack a dawn thing I I woke up at 6 30
rolled over hit snooze woke up at 7 30.
then I
and then I I picked up my phone and
Twitter had bumped you know to to my
notification list this amazing amazing
thing and I opened it right away and
just read through you know I was I was
like oh man like good morning to me and
then I see this tweet and then you know
before I know it I'm halfway through my
eyes are wide open I'm like you know
your heart heartbeats racing you know
following this story that they got on
here so it's pretty sick not gonna lie
yeah I love these little these posts
because every once in a while like
there's a there's this group of people
especially Sam
um zlc and Zaya like those two they're
the common denominator across all the
different groups I think yeah and
generally it'll be like they'll be like
a couple months like things will be just
like going by like nothing's happening
and then out of nowhere like they'll be
like uh a five page blog post that's
like detailing how they hacked some core
infrastructure within like the global
internet or something it'll be like we
hacked undersea cables we had tlds we
hacked all the car like start like
engine remote start stop [__] like it's
like it's crazy yeah it's crazy I mean
we talked about that sort of tendency on
episode 17
um you know the live episode that we did
in in LA and it just some particularly
Sam has an uncanny ability to just find
critical internet infrastructure and
like destroy it so it's kind of nuts
yeah like these I like the thing that I
have these same kinds of thought
processes but then they end kind of
where I'm like oh that's interesting I
wonder how that works and then I just
move on yeah or uh they don't have a bug
Bounty program move along you know like
yeah I feel like I'm too I feel like I'm
too focused on that like I feel like I
don't know and it's also a little bit of
a of a ballsy thing you know like I
haven't done a lot of
um just let's call it good faith
security research right I think that's
the term that they use in the uh you
know yes or whatever that is the
modified tour of yes exactly yeah and so
like I I haven't done a lot of good
faith security research
um and you know just for fear of you
know crossing boundaries causing people
a nightmare that sort of thing but um
you know every time they drop a blog
post about the stuff they've done you
know I think man like if somebody else
had done this this would have been a
nightmare for the whole internet right
and uh you know at this point Sam Sam
and Squad have saved the internet like
six times so
um I I have to I have to respect that
you know whether or not I agree with the
going out of out of scope or not yeah
yeah no it's true I think like now we're
starting to get it to an Era where that
type of work is a lot more like okay and
allowed and stuff but you know five ten
years ago this wouldn't have been like
if you did this there was actual serious
risk that something really bad could
happen like you could just get charged
by like you know and like jail yeah you
know like you know you're hacking like
such core infrastructure that this stuff
can be taken the wrong way but I think
we're finally starting to get to a point
and especially with the laws and
everything that have changed that like
security research especially ethical
like white hat security research is a
lot more accepted and mainstream and so
you know coming from that approach I
think Sam said especially with all the
experience Sam has Sam has done this so
many times with so many other companies
and I don't mean that in like a negative
way like that's just like his his jam
and that's cool same just hacks whatever
man yeah he sees something interesting
he's like I'm gonna hack that that's
like it you know once he's gonna hack it
he's gonna hack it and so I think he has
figured out the right ways to
communicate that with companies in a way
that's such that he doesn't come across
as like threatening or like anything
like legal and I think he's even said
privately only a handful of times like
literally like a couple of times has it
ever even edged towards like the case
where like things would be going
negatively in the communications and it
never actually ended up that way it was
just kind of like this is sketchy
Communications let's just like uh you
know move on and it gets over with
yeah yeah for sure man no I I respect
that and and I will I will confess I
recently succumbed to the Temptation and
hack the cool Target that I wanted to
hack
um and I have not gotten any response
back despite following Sam's template
and I didn't put any but you know the
way that because I hit him up I was like
all right Sam like I did the thing how
do I how do I tell people about it right
and Sam's like all right you should do
this this and so I followed his
instructions and uh I really like the
way that he approaches it because it's
very non-threatening it's very
um
it's very
professional and and you know cards on
the table for word you know and uh and
so I really I really like that um we
should definitely we should have them on
the Pod and to talk about that specific
thing I'll note that down for a future
topic because that that is a pretty cool
unique feature of Sam Sam at all uh uh
you know going after these sort of out
of scope things and and the way that
they deal with it I think is something
that the community could benefit from
yeah for sure this was actually
reminding me now that we're thinking
about it that we're talking about like
contacting website owners and stuff
there was a really interesting repo that
popped up on my Twitter feed and we'll
link this in the show notes is by John
Keegan and it's called behind this
website and it's essentially a checklist
it's on GitHub
um and it's a checklist of things that
you can go through to try and identify
who actually owns a website so it's
stuff like are there authors listed what
is the local time of the websites does
it have an RSS feed do they have links
to like Facebook and Twitter if so do
they have contact info on the Facebook
page here's where you can find it all
that kind of stuff and I think for like
security research especially if you're
hacking like a website that doesn't have
a bug bending program may not have like
a security contact or something like
that yeah this is probably a good way to
try and get some of those other direct
lines of contact because I know this is
something that Sam struggles with like
it's very hit or miss some of the
websites that he'll be hacking like
he'll try and reach out to somebody and
it's impossible to get through how to
like go to LinkedIn have to go to
Twitter you'll have to hit up like
random employees who are working at the
company on like random social media so
this uh this might be something that's
useful if you're not getting a lot of
traction with your with your initial
email
yeah send it over I definitely want to
check it out and I think like I've kind
of poked around on on like LinkedIn and
some other places and trying to find you
know the right person to come in contact
with and I think I think the other thing
is that I don't know you know what Sam's
LinkedIn presence is but I feel like if
you had a bigger LinkedIn presence you
know I feel like that might help because
you could just kind of like you know
reach out to your network and we're all
like you know seven degrees away from
like some obscure person on the other
side of the world so I'm sure somehow
you could you could get in contact with
the right people if you had a big enough
presence and sort of a professional
Network yeah for sure I was actually uh
I was wondering this uh this the website
you know we got a little derailed here
about the website that posted this blog
post
hackcompute.com yeah I saw that yeah
first of all never heard of them uh and
I was looking into it and I have a
feeling we might be hearing more from uh
from this group in the future because
they have nothing posted on this blog
except for a forward from January six
months ago that's like talking about how
the industry has changed and all this
stuff and you know we like you know now
we just hack stuff for like good and uh
you know how this group will like focus
on really high impact stuff and then six
months later they post this this blog
about hacking the TLD cctld you know
yeah like like this group of people you
know Sam Brett Rhys and and Chubbs
they're just like hey let's make this
like cool hacker group and then like
pone the internet and then yeah cool
what's the what's the most crazy thing
we could go for okay well what if we
could control every single domain in the
whole internet yeah yeah exactly and
then they just you know it takes them
what T minus five months not even
probably because they they're probably
having this conversation way before that
so yeah 100 super super cool
um yeah but oh my gosh dude look at this
if you look at the if you I just saw
this you know if you look at the
telegram communication they were having
with this guy about halfway through the
hacking Epp servers blog post it says
January 14th
no but they created their initial
forward on January 18th so okay gotcha
gotcha so they you know they've they
yeah maybe it was the other way around
maybe they were just like oh what if we
hacked the whole internet yeah as a cool
security
so I'm hoping to see some more stuff
from the from this group these are some
real Heavy Hitters and I'll be curious
if it's just gonna be like that that
Core group of people or if they're gonna
Branch out and just do like just blog
posts with anybody who's doing this kind
of hacking or or what it is but
um yeah but it would be interesting to
see for sure yeah definitely give that
that blog post a read it's super
consumable it's very straightforward and
it's an awesome example of just the old
outdated foldable infrastructure that's
all over the place on the internet
yeah for sure So speaking of consumable
blog posts another Banger from that
shubs tweeted out
um is this this one that just popped up
this morning actually so I'm really glad
we recorded the Pod today because you
know sheb's tweeted shubs at all you
know tweeted the the crazy Epp server
thing last night and then this morning
he tweeted this and I'm just like man
these are like right top of the list
um yeah so this next one we wanted to
talk about was a write-up by uh a group
apparently called summoning.team uh I
guess that's the name of the company
um and this is on a couple cves that
were released earlier this uh this year
for
um via mware V realize Network Insight
um and this was a really cool
vulnerability
um and I just I love I love stuff
surrounding nginx configurations after
after my uh you know life and death
experience with the nginx configuration
files uh with Sam herb last year that we
presented on it defcom so I love I love
reading um nginx related stuff and
as sheb said in his tweet you know this
is like a crazy A crazy cool
um little twist on uh nginx reverse
proxies so essentially the tldr of this
I don't know did you get to review it or
not yeah I reviewed some of it oh nice
okay cool yeah so the tldr of this was
you know it's a pretty straightforward
command injection
um and and you actually see this the the
um procedure that they used to get it
was create support bundle and this is
something that I've actually seen a lot
in Enterprise software is like there's
normally some sort of weird endpoint
somewhere that it allows you to create a
bundle for support so that you know they
can send off all the logs and stuff like
that to you know the team to provide you
know support for the product yeah and of
course you know the way the way that
these sort of like Dev oriented back-end
functionalities get it implemented is of
course just calling stuff straight from
the command line
um so you get a pretty textbook uh
command injection there but I think the
cool part was the nginx the nginx bug
and it took me a second to sort of
realize what was going on here but the
reverse proxy that they have in place is
supposed to be filtering out a a
specific
route which is this SAS rest to SAS
servlet location and and for the first
time I looked at I don't know if you had
the same thing Joel but I was like man I
feel like this should be really obvious
to bypass but it's not you know
um because they're just like reverse
proxy to the same location on the back
end
um but what ended up doing it was you
know this sort of it's not really an off
by slash sort of thing it's pretty close
to that but just abusing the sort of dot
um dot functionality in directories and
the way that nginx takes care of that to
be able to hit the same endpoint on the
back end that you would have only been
able to hit via the first little
location snippet there
um and and so it's kind of hard to
explain over over audio but it's a
really cool bypass so we'll link it down
in the show notes and definitely check
it out if you enjoy nginx configuration
stuff yeah so basically like when you
have like nginx figs you have like these
location like routes that basically say
like anything under this path or maybe
matching this regex should be handled
like by this route like this by these
rules and
if apparently this is something new to
me I didn't know this but yeah if you
put like a DOT slash before your path
that's equivalent in routing it's
equivalent to like going to that path
but it gets handled differently by the
nginx config so that lets you bypass
like the nginx config rule but still hit
that path and be able to hit the path
that you weren't supposed to access with
no one yeah so crazy yeah it is it's
pretty cool I really like it a lot
um yeah it looks like the person um
behind this blog by the way I was
looking a little bit in the about
section on the summoning team and it
says that I don't know if it's a team of
people if it's just this one person but
uh it says their name is Cinna and
they're a bone researcher and they link
out to their Twitter Synology uh they
are a Pon to own uh participant they
work on Microsoft MVR uh so yeah it
seems like uh somebody who knows knows
their stuff and uh is definitely not
their their first time around this this
type of stuff so this is pretty dope
nice dude that's that's pretty rad I I
just followed them on Twitter definitely
going to try to keep up with that I I
definitely I definitely want to
I definitely want to at some point
participate in pone to own like I think
that's gonna be on the bucket The Bucket
List item for a while you know we hacker
one keeps us pretty busy with the live
hacking events that that we we run here
but at some point I may have to be like
you know what I'm just going to take the
next couple months and focus on related
stuff because that'd be a cool bucket
list item I think yeah yeah 100 I I have
the same the same goal
yeah all right
um so that's let's see uh oh yeah the
other the only other thing I wanted to
bring up in the news section for today
was um literally right before this this
call again so once again the news
killing it I'm glad we we decided to
record when we did
um Roy from Zoom the guy that runs the
zoom bug Bounty program tweeted out a
zoom's new sort of vulnerability impact
scoring system
um and Jill and I were privy to this
because we uh they're actually we'd
heard about it before
through some channels
um but you know they just released it
and essentially
um it's a new it's a replacement for
CVSs
and I don't know man what what do you
think about it I I it's kind of this is
try this is like uh you know they're
they're like you do you know what a back
rhythm is
a what a acronym okay a background is
like when you when you yeah it's like
when you take like uh you have an
acronym that you want and you come up
with words that fit that acronym that
describe it right so it's like you'll
see this a lot with like Congressional
bills and stuff oh y'all have like uh
fancy like short name for it that's like
pronounceable like a real word or
something yeah and then each letter
stands for some like ridiculously long
yeah but it doesn't like perfectly
correlated to the concept like oh like
yeah it's like started with the with the
acronym and then worked back I like yeah
exactly yeah so it's called a background
this feels like a background for like
trying to figure out how you're supposed
to codify Bounty payments you know what
I mean like instead of just looking at
it and being like this is this impact
and we should be paying this much
because it's that bad according to a
table
you're like all right we have to like
break this down into like like
completely consistent across the board
segments that we can then like plug into
a uniform system and get like reliable
output results back and like that's
awesome but that is like I feel like
it's trying to over complicate us uh
like a solution for a problem that
doesn't really exist
yeah yeah man I mean I don't know I feel
like there is a problem like I feel like
CVSs is definitely not amazing
um but it's something that we've become
used to and I think VSS or Viss which is
the the thing that they named it
um
I don't know just for me as a bug Bounty
Hunter it increases my risk and my
friction for using you know for
reporting bugs to zoom because it's like
okay now I've got to go read this whole
spec that you invented so you know so
you've definitely got the upper hand
here right and and you know I don't know
I don't know anything about any of the
metrics you know like I don't it's not
like a small spec either by the way no
it's not it's a long spot it's a long
spec
it's very complex it's probably as dense
or more dense than cpss itself yeah yeah
and and so you know on one hand I like
to see a good stab taken at you know
CVSs and the current vulnerability you
know metric system but on the other hand
I feel like this misses the mark on the
on the side of Simplicity you know maybe
this covers you know everything that
they wanted it to cover but for me as a
bug Bounty Hunter
um my risk just doubled or tripled you
know to to report a bug here so I think
overall it will negatively impact their
their bug Bounty program
um just from a participation perspective
and then
um yeah
yeah I don't know I guess we'll see how
it plays out if more people adopt it
that could not be the case but you know
we'll kind of see yeah I mean I've seen
a couple other programs trying to do
similar stuff to this
um yeah even when I worked at Uber Uber
tried to do a similar thing to this and
we found that it was just like really
really complicated to try and do it for
all bugs there were certain things where
we where we could like certainly codify
the bounties
um like generally speaking xss was
something that you could like you know
depending on what type of xss and then
maybe there was a modifying Factor if
it's like particularly sensitive or the
report shows additional impact or
something like that but you know
generally speaking like we we would be
able to pay an excess the same like
across the board but that's not the case
for every kind of bug and trying to do
that for it for like everything
uniformly every single type of bug
within one system is very very difficult
um yeah so totally I'll be interested to
see how this actually pans out I think
using this as like part of their
calculation would be a great idea but
using it for the whole calculation just
leaves a lot of room for like oh the
calculator says this even though we
don't agree with it we're gonna pay it
because the calculator says that and
that's consistent right and I I don't
think that is going to land great
yeah I agree man and and who knows you
know I think I think hackers are gonna
hack and and you know someone will
probably read through this whole spec
and figure out okay how can I you know
Ika hire a crit out of something that I
find on a pretty regular basis you know
with the configuration tenants with the
different metrics in this guy so you
know um maybe it'll work out in the
favor of the hacker I just I just feel
pretty uh being on the hacking side I
feel I feel apprehensive yeah you just
have to figure out how to game game the
the calculator so that you get the
highest score possible with the least
effort and then yeah the calculator says
it I don't know that's what the guys you
know that's when you know whenever
programs stick very
um you know intensely to to CVSs uh I
know a couple people that are that will
just not okay on a specific very high
paying program that just will hold on to
their bugs and figure out like some
weird Fringe way to affect like
Integrity even if it's a confidentiality
bug and then like you just get that
extra bump which is like you know at
that point it's like 10 grand and you're
like cha-ching yeah yeah exactly yeah
cool pretty good um I see you have a
note in here that says do you ask
yourself why on Black Box testing and I
was curious what that meant okay all
right let me let me explain this and
there's a tweet going out about this
later today
um it'll it'll land before the Pod drops
but
um on this on this
um live hacking event scope that we're
that we're working on
um
I've run into a bug or two
that really I I decided I feel like I
moved too quickly sometimes on these
sort of things I like oh cool a bug and
then I like report it and then you know
and and not that I necessarily move on
but that I'll just like keep searching
but I think I need to pause for a second
I really need to put some like CPU
Cycles into by that I mean you know
brain energy into uh into like why did
that work like what does this bug tell
me about
the mistakes that companies will be
making in their infrastructure and in in
their coding practices and what can I
determine about that that might help me
find similar bugs and and I just I don't
you know I've heard people sort of talk
about this before but I'm not sure I've
ever sat down and actually put like five
minutes of thought into all right well
you know if this you know happens here
then maybe you know this is what's
happening on the back end and just kind
of work through that whole
um thought progression and because I did
that this time I found some interesting
stuff so I just wanted to see what your
thoughts were on that yeah no that's
really interesting
um I think that's a great approach
because oftentimes when something goes
wrong it's a systemic problem it doesn't
mean that it's like implemented
like in one place and it's affecting
multiple things that could be what it is
but oftentimes it's that like a
developer has seen a pattern somewhere
else and they're just copying that
pattern or maybe uh the you know they
just literally made like a single
one-off mistake and that happens too
where it's only in one spot and it may
not be a common issue but trying to
understand what
you know what led them to make that that
you know logical leap or whatever to
actually write that error into the code
like
trying to figure that out and then play
on that like later down the line even if
it's not within the same field so say
it's you find an eye door through some
specific case
you can test that idor with the same ID
the same type of ID in other places but
I would also test that same eye door
like method or whatever with other IDs
in other places because it could be that
it's not like specific to a user ID for
example it could be that it's also
working on group IDs or whatever type of
IDs exist right yeah absolutely no I
love that tip and and I think this is
where being in your shoes as a as
someone who reads you know large
corporation back-end code on a regular
basis I think that really helps for
mapping out like what
what could possibly be happening and why
a specific vulnerability would be in
place because like for me I did like you
know
a year of PHP Dev when I was 18 years
old at like a startup incubator you know
and that's the that's the extent of my
my you know knowledge of of back-end
writing code processes right so I don't
have much to lean on there but I feel
like if you if you have a little bit
more of an understanding of how things
might be implemented especially when
companies release these um these docs
that that sort of talk about their back
end architecture like and and by the way
I did check we we can release who who's
in this life hacking event this is zoom
in Salesforce yeah
um and uh and you know I'll just call
I'll just give them a shout out right
away Salesforce um you know they they
dropped some really really nice
um public documentation they put it all
in a dock for us during this event and
it made it so much easier to understand
what's happening
um you know in the back end and I I kind
of read through a bunch of that and
um I think when I found bugs and I
started correlating it to the way that
their infrastructure is designed things
started to be become a little bit more
clear and that's the kind of stuff you
like to to have when you're trying to
find all these books so yeah for sure I
mean some of these companies have way
better documentation than others
um you know Salesforce uh I would like
to say specifically what the like things
within it yeah I I wouldn't I wouldn't
okay so you uh you can imagine what I'm
talking I know what you're talking about
one of them has pretty good
documentation but then a lot of the
endpoints that I'll be looking at that
seem fairly basic I'll look it up and
I'll expect to find ox and there's
nothing for it yeah yeah yeah so so it
really varies but I I that's also like
one of the awesome things is if a
company has extensive documentation read
through it and try and find things that
are inconsistent or sound like weird
functionality because it might be
something that's vulnerable by design
that you can exploit to your advantage
or it might just be something that
doesn't line up with how it's actually
behaving in the real world and then
that's a perfect use case where you can
say hey the docs say it should be
behaving this way it's actually not
Bounty yeah the vulnerability the
vulnerable by Design thing sort of just
I don't know man I I've gotten burned on
that a couple times because there are
some really poor architecting decisions
happening at like a very large level
with some of these big companies that
we're hacking on all the time right and
and I as I try to point some of these
out they're like
yeah that's what we told the dev team
when they wrote the project so internal
dupe but I'm like okay but you still let
them make it actually you know like yeah
I don't know maybe security just doesn't
have enough sway in these larger
corporations but you know you hate to
see stuff like that because it I mean it
puts users at so much risk and it also
pisses off about bounty hunters yeah
yeah it's like a weird State because
some of some of it is accepted risk it's
like you know they know that this is an
issue but it's not like an issue that
they consider to be an issue so they're
it's like you know if it becomes public
then that doesn't really matter to them
and maybe they'll change it then but you
know a lot of the time there's just not
enough effort to an accepted risk is one
thing but like
and and if they say that then that's
fine and I'm gonna I'm gonna blog about
it you know because at least some of the
stuff that I'm that I'm thinking of
right now you know you can see me just
hold himself back he's like his blood
pressure is 180 over 30. you know like
yeah and so man my Art's gonna explode
Joel yeah
um
but yeah you know if they if they I
think the users need to be the company
can accept the risk but users are need
to be able to make an informed decision
about
um you know if they accept that risk
when utilizing a certain service
provider and I think that's where a
little bit of a disconnect comes because
I can write my blog all I want and you
know as a you know medium-sized player
in the security World maybe you know 50
000 people or 100 000 people will read
it or something like that on a good day
but you know that doesn't of that
information is not trickling all the way
down to the users that are making the
decision to use that service writer on a
on a you know daily weekly basis
um and so I don't know there's a little
bit of a disconnect there this is the
ramblings of a frustrated security
researcher but yeah there's not a really
great solution out there in in our
current you know State and yeah that is
what it is yeah cool all right you want
to hit the main topic for this episode
yeah man I think that was the longest
News segment we've ever done like and it
was news plus like you know bug Bounty
Revelations or whatever but yeah um yeah
but we'll keep it a little tight today
because you know we're both in in the
Life hacking event and just kind of
chilling uh you know on pod stuff
instead and focusing on hacking stuff
but
um the thing that we wanted to talk
about today was uh doing some some uh
I don't know just drop in some cool
physical setup stuff that we've got
um I've got a pretty cool hacking setup
from my perspective but I realized
recently you know the perspective you're
getting in the background might need
some work because if you look at like
stulk and J Haddix and some of the other
guys like you know when you hop on a
video call with them it's like boom you
know like and they're like in their
hacker Den with the lights coming on you
know and like cool things spinning in
the background and so I think I need to
kind of level up on that front I know me
too I like I see some of those like Nam
as well he has like oh yeah as well for
sure you know all these people have like
really amazing like backgrounds that are
like set up and like designed they got
like little like Trinkets and stuff that
like fill the space and I just got like
15 posters behind me
yeah I ought to hit Stoke up because I I
want to say I saw something somewhere
about someone flying Stoke out somewhere
to help them design their sort of like
hacker setup you know and unfortunately
Stoke doesn't make it over to the east
coast very often but maybe I'll do like
a virtual Consulting session with him
and be like stalk how do I make this
cool yeah yeah for sure yeah so to that
end
um you know basically
as people who spend all day at a
computer and at a desk like generally
speaking we think it's very worthwhile
to put your money where your butt is
right and so that that's like your
keyboard your mouse your monitors your
desk your chair your environment that
you're working in like all that stuff
like you know if it's where you're
spending
eight plus hours a day a third of your
life then
should probably make an investment right
it's just like a bed right buy a good
mattress buy good you know if you're
walking a lot buy good shoes if you're
sitting a lot buying a chair if you're
using your computer a lot by a computer
yeah no for sure man I I totally agree
and I had a little
um you know anecdote that I wanted to
share on this behalf you know when I was
in college I was pretty busy uh I worked
at a i interned at
um a big company Dominion Energy in
Richmond and so I was biking back and
forth from Dominion to my school you
know on a regular basis so I was I was
staying you know pretty active and I
graduated and I got my first hacking job
and
um I feel like you know a year and a
half two years just kind of blew by and
then I remember sitting at my apartment
you know and realizing like man
I'm not very active right now like what
why am I why do I have what is this fat
that's on the lower side of my bed you
know like what is going on here
um and I was like yeah you know what uh
you know it's fine I'm probably not too
far along let me just go like hit the
treadmill for a little bit and so I hit
the treadmill and I ran like you know
0.25 miles and I was like you know I was
dying
yeah and I just also you know I realized
my posture had sort of changed from
staying at the desk just for just from
like a year and a half and I think I was
just kind of blinded by you know the new
career the new setup you know sort of
grinding on book Bounty and hacking
stuff at the time and I totally put out
the window you know the personal fitness
and the posture and that sort of thing
um Investments that needed to be made to
save me some time you know and energy
and and since then you know I've I've
remediated a lot of those issues and we
can talk about some of the stuff that
I've done to do that today but I just
wanted to you know say this for anyone
listening that kind of finds himself in
that similar scenario the long the
longer you wait on this
the harder it gets right I don't care if
you've been doing this for 10 years if
you do it for 15 years if you do it for
11 years you do it for 10 years and six
months it's going to be harder than it
was at 10 years right so like for sure
you know you need to make those
Lifestyle Changes ASAP and and it
doesn't have to be drastic but it should
be intentional I think because
um it's all too easy to kind of Let It
Go and then have it become unmanageable
yeah for sure um have you always been
like a computer person like sitting like
using computers growing up oh hell yeah
dude okay yeah I I started really
getting into computers I was like 10.
yeah same okay so I don't know if it's
similar for you but like I'm in my
mid-20s I have lower back pain already
like just from sitting all day like you
know if I sit too much or if I'm hunched
over at my desk for like even for like
one day if I have like a long day where
i'm particularly like heads down and I'm
like bent over like my back I'll feel it
for sure and I have to do like certain
stretches and stuff to like stretch out
my lower back
yeah I don't know man I haven't had
lower lower back quite as much
um but I do notice that my posture you
know suffers for sure like I definitely
have you know computer neck sometimes
you know and I'm like got my neck
forwarded that sort of thing and I've
always been you know I I think I sort of
shouted Corbin out on the Pod when he
came on but like you know if you look at
any of the uh the hack one media you
know Corbin's a good looking guy for
sure so there's that that helps as well
but I think he shows up in a lot of
hacker one photos because he's just got
such a like he's got good posture he's
got a good build you know like yeah in
any of the yeah
yeah he doesn't have the gamer neck you
know and it's because he's putting in
the Reps at the gym man I've talked to
him about that I was like you know what
kind of exercises are you doing and
stuff like that and he he attributes a
lot of that to deadlift and and stuff
like that so I don't know you know I do
deadlift do you deadlift I used to a
little bit honestly my main concern is
injuring myself
um yeah like I think if I was gonna do I
was gonna talk about this so yeah like
doing workouts and stuff that are
specific to your work environment is
something that's super helpful right
like again you sit all day do like Ab
Core like lower back workouts and stuff
like that that's gonna build those
muscles because
inherently by sitting and not using them
those muscles aren't getting worked and
they're not going to be as strong as the
rest of your muscles right we're gonna
have like you know pretty like good
muscles and like our arms and whatever
from like typing and like using you know
our eyes we're not going to get eye
strained to the same effect and all that
kind of stuff but like yeah you know the
other areas are where it's going to
suffer so I think targeting those areas
and it doesn't have to be deadless you
can do like there's other school you
know squats and and you can do like uh
leg presses and whatever like you know
there's there's lots of stuff that you
can do to build those those muscles
you you've got a standing desk Rachel I
do yeah I should actually [__] use it
I was gonna say like I feel like every
time I record the Pod whenever I'm
recording the Pod you know there's just
a certain amount of energy that I want
to put into it and I just feel like that
matches standing way better than sitting
so like 90 of the time when we're
recording the Pod I'm standing at my
desk
um and I do I stand at my desk and maybe
like
maybe like once or twice a day
um you know normally when I'm just doing
hacking and just working on normal stuff
um you see dude that that that actually
looks that looks better with your
background too you know yeah if you get
that lamp out of there though get it
locked in you've actually got a pretty
good setup I think yeah that works well
maybe I should be standing more
how tall are the ceilings in your in
your room uh there are eight feet the
standard height yeah normal eight feet
yeah nice now that that looks good sorry
sorry a few people no I'm not uh yeah
it doesn't hit the top yeah exactly um
yeah so I mean what uh I I've for me I
use um uplift desks and I think they're
great man it's worth it your uplift as
well yep yeah yeah I think uh I think
it's really nice and I did want to do a
shout out to Mariah here um you know I
uh I I have an L uplift desk so I I
bought you know I've had it you know I
bought one of their their fully designed
products and had it sent to me but
Mariah actually just bought the she has
an uplift desk as well and she just
bought the legs and she went to Home
Depot and got a butcher block top yep
and oiled it up and like you know got it
looking pretty and then I just you know
we just screwed it on top of the yeah
and it looks super good
um way better than mine uh that I just
bought directly from uplift so
um that's a really good opportunity as
well and I think it only cost her like
150 bucks totally yeah yeah so really
depends on the size that you're going
for
um the legs like just buying the legs
like independently like that's like a
great solution especially maybe you
already have a desk desktop that you
like and you can take it off for me I
wanted a huge desk like I like having a
lot of space on my desk I keep a lot of
stuff on my desk I have like speakers
and monitors and my PC is on my desk and
all that kind of stuff so
um I like having like as much space as I
could when I was looking at standing
desk uplift desk had the largest uh
standing desk that I could find and I
think it's like 84 inches or something
long it's like it's wow dude it's huge
yeah so it's great like I have much more
space than I would ever need
um and the top you know if you buy the
top directly from them like finding a
piece of you know hardwood material or
something like that that that's that
large to get shipped to you is about the
same price and hard to find so
um I ended up just getting the top with
them but I think did you get an L or did
you no no I have a fully straight one I
have a friend who has
um like the L shape with like it's a
long portion and they have a shorter
like L portion
um and I had really thought about that
but uh uh it's it really depends on the
room like that that's what I found I I
moved with this desk uh one or two times
and depending on what your office layout
is is going to depend on whether or not
that desk is really going to work in the
room so I didn't want to have to keep
like buying rebuying desks and all that
kind of stuff so I just stuck with like
a straight long desk
um but I will probably eventually
replace the replace this and I'm not
sure if I'll do the same I've got like
the I've got like the five by
four I think yeah is is what it and and
I'm not gonna lie it's a little tight I
think you know I I think it could be and
it fits my room perfectly so I'm glad I
bought it
um and I'm not planning on moving lunch
I think maybe I'll move you know one or
two times in my in the rest of my life
probably
um and so I'm I didn't you know I
decided to buy the desk for this space
um but yeah I think I think next time I
would go with a six no this is actually
a six this is a six by this is a six by
four
um I think I think next time I would go
a little bit bigger though because it
does help to have that additional room
over to the side and especially when
you've got an L shape you're and I'm and
I've got my monitor set up which I'll
talk about in a second which I
absolutely love by the way
um you know it takes up a good chunk of
the desk and I need some more some
workspace as well like for example when
we were doing the hardware hacking stuff
I had to set up this little table you
know behind me here to get to get the
hardware hacking stuff at a good spot
because if I was trying to do it on this
table everything just got too crowded
yeah well that's actually a tip that
that I didn't write it down but I think
that's a good one I have
um
let me see if I can hold this up
yeah yeah
so I have this uh I have this like
portable table it's got a little knob up
here so you can basically you can raise
and lower it as you want it's on Wheels
it's on these casters awesome um and
essentially I I keep it underneath my
desk all the time and then if I ever
need extra space I just wheel it out I
raise it up to the height I want lock it
portable table good to go you can lock
the wheels if you want
um and I have one or two of those like I
keep one of them in my office I keep
another one like somewhere else in the
house but when I'm doing like the
hardware hacking stuff for example even
I don't have enough room on my desk for
you know all that hard like all the all
the builders and stuff Mr seven foot
desk over here doesn't have enough room
on his desk that's correct so even with
my seven foot desk I don't have enough I
don't have enough room for it so I like
having those extra portable like
flexible spaces and yeah I actually have
another one right back here I don't know
yeah but um yeah that also is like it's
just sort of like a portable tabletop
that I can pull out I use it for like
eating I'll use it for various things
but having that available do the Wheels
lock on it
uh this one's not on Wheels but the
other one does yeah it has locking
Wheels yeah that's cool I I hadn't
really thought about getting a little
side table like that that's that's you
know flexible for the space that's
that's not a bad idea yeah and it's sort
of like flexible like you know tabletop
Space is really useful so that you don't
have to like reorganize your desk if you
want to do something big
yeah for sure okay cool so dude I just I
yeah let's talk monitors because I'm I
just
you know I feel like most people don't
realize that like you're in front of a
[__] space station like like dude I
am man and it's so freaking great it's
like this is literally a childhood dream
fulfilled okay so let me let me lay this
out for you okay so like I mentioned
I've been into computers since I was
like you know 10 12 that that sort of
range right and uh I have pretty you
know I don't have a great memory of my
like childhood it's just all kind of
like oh yeah that was pretty good you
know so especially timelines you know it
wasn't great so it's like somewhere back
in the in most of the time that I can
remember I was in love with computers
but I do remember the point when I
became in love with computers and I've
talked about this on the Pod before but
it was just one time this guy for my
church came over and he typed into a you
know black command line box and fixed
the Internet so I could play my games
and I was like dude that was really cool
I gotta learn how to do that so anyway I
you know I'd see him every Sunday
because they're going to church every
Sunday and
so I'd start you ask him hey you know
how can I learn about this bloody bloody
blah and being the awesome guy that he
is he like brought me to his work which
was a university uh the university that
I ended up going to by the way
um and uh and he was like check out like
the setup right so I walk into his
office and you know he's like a sis
admin or something like that I think
he's higher up now but and the guy has
six monitors and it's like you know
three on the top three on the bottom
just like massive arrays like graphs
going off on all of them he's like
monitoring this and that and the other
thing and I was like dude
this is sick and from that moment on I
was like I know someday I'm gonna have
that I gotta set it up and then finally
when we moved back from Japan I'm like
all right I might actually stay in this
house for more than a year which we
hadn't done since I was like 17 at that
point
um and and so I invested and I bought a
uh and right right as I was getting
ready to build the setup dude I went to
do you guys have like the restore near
you do you know what that is restore the
restore like the furniture store the
Habitat for Humanity thing yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah so dude I you know
most people I think they listen to the
Pod know I do real estate stuff on the
side so I was going to the the restore
to to get some stuff for my real estate
projects and I walk in there and I see
like 12
um 27 inch 4K HP monitors
what the heck can I walk over there and
they're 40 bucks each dude dude these
are 400 monitors they're selling for
forty dollars so I said I run over the
desk I'm like I I'm I'm buying all of
those and I just slam my wallet down on
the counter and I'm like I I'm buying
all of those and he's like okay all
right you know we'll get someone to help
you move them to your car this is the
real version of the of the fry Shut Up
And Take My Money just take it shut up
and take my money man because he was
like oh I was so happy and so you know I
walk out of there
so some of them weren't 4K or whatever
so I was like you know we'll leave those
yeah uh you know but um you know I think
I ended up getting like seven or eight
27 inch 4K monitors man and I was
thrilled
um so what I'm looking at right now is
I've got an up uplift sort of monitor
mount setup I've got four 27 inch
monitors 4K monitors in a square and and
I you know I realized after I got this I
was like pin I don't
I don't have a computer that can pick in
the handle for 20 so I ended up having
to buy this crazy computer that we'll
talk about later but um I finally got it
set up and it's like I have full vision
of all of them and man does it help with
testing because you know you can just
segment your different accounts to a
different Monitor and it's like man it's
so much easier to keep your session
straight so yeah I I really I think it's
really really great for a bug Bounty
Hunter nice that's awesome yeah I am
nothing close to that I have I have he
says I am nothing I have nothing you
like no not like I'm like my presence
yes I'm like an elementary school child
compared to Justin I have two 1440p
monitors they're both uh this they're
both 27 inches
um it's a good number man 27. it feels
good yeah one's uh 75 Hertz the other
one is 244 Hertz the main like my main
one in front of me is the 244 Hertz so
it's like a really nice like uh you can
do like gaming and it's like super high
refresh rate so it looks great it's IPS
so it has really accurate colors all
that kind of stuff so that's like my
main like straight straight on Monitor
and then to my side I have just for like
that's the 75 Hertz for everything else
then I also
uh it's not really a monitor but it's
like my laptop I I have it's it's like a
monitor arm kind of like what I use for
for my microphone here it's like a
Pneumatic arm but on the end of it it
has a flat laptop plate that I can just
put my laptop on and I just holds my
laptop in the air and it's mounted to my
desk so if I move my desk up laptop
comes with me if I move my desk down
laptop comes with me all the cables and
everything are like Tethered to this I
can just like pull it closer to me if I
want I can move it further away just on
an arm it just floats use a Mac right
yep so so I mean when you do you have
how do you mount that into your setup do
you have like a mounting station or is
there like just single cord or what yeah
so depending on what I'm doing I I'll
use like
um a hub for the most part I don't have
to plug like so much stuff in my router
is like right here so I get like
Crazy Fast speeds over Wi-Fi as it is so
I really don't need to be plugged in
over ethernet but if I do I have a
switch right behind my PC which is right
next to it and I can just plug it in I
have a like a ethernet cable that's just
not plugged in it's just right here and
I can I can just plug it in if I need to
um behind my monitor I have like a
clamshell dock because I I have two
laptops actually have a work laptop my
personal laptop
so it has two slots and then that will
plug into my main monitor so it's a
little bit of a complex setup what is a
clamshell uh what is that
oh he's gonna he's gonna try to go get
it man here we go it's it's actually 3D
printed this I designed to 3D printed
this no way dude yeah yeah so this it's
just it holds two laptops like this you
just slot them in you know
um and then they just like sit on their
Edge and when they're plugged in they'll
still work and stuff but you don't have
to have them open
um so I have it set up so that if I want
to use a laptop on my monitor setup I'll
put it in clamshell plug I'll just like
put it in my stand I'll plug in an HDMI
cable I have a button on my stream deck
uh which I use to set my PC to only
display on the secondary monitor okay
this is like it's a little hacky okay
but basically like Windows you can have
it mirror or extend or display only on
one or only on the other right so I tell
it okay only display on one monitor my
the main monitor in front of me then
goes oh there's no input on DVI I'm
gonna fall back to whatever has an input
which is the laptop that's plugged in on
HDMI and then oh man that is yes and
then I have this piece of software it's
amazing it's by a company called
seamless and it's called Synergy it's
been around for a while it's basically a
software KVM and it allows me to
configure all of my computers with like
a client server thing the server runs on
my PC and then I have a client on my
laptops and I can
seamlessly move my mouse and keyboard
across screens to different computers
it's instant like there's no latency no
nothing I I've used this for like years
and it's yeah no way yeah that's that's
pretty freaking cool yeah yeah I use it
on on the daily basis like I have I
don't even notice it like every once in
a while if there's like Network stuff
going on internally then I'll have like
maybe like a jump or something on the
mouse but like it's generally latency
list so I can use the same message let
me just confirm this here so you've got
two laptops your work laptop and you're
in your personal laptop and then you've
got a desktop computer yep and that runs
in Windows and that runs Windows okay
and so you run Synergy on the desktop
computer you have Synergy running on
your client running on your laptops and
that allows you to uh you know sort of
pull the display onto your your desktop
and then you can just kind of seamlessly
jump between all of these Yeah so
basically I can use the same keyboard
and mouse from my PC I can even do like
rebindings and stuff so for example like
mac uses command right so I have Synergy
set up to automatically rebind my like
command key and my option Keys such that
I don't have to change like my hand
position on my keyboard when I cross OS
so if I do like Ctrl C or whatever it's
in the same spot as it would be on a Mac
and I just my brain just does the back
and forth
um so yeah that's what I use I just use
one keyboard and mouse from my PC across
to my other devices and then I use my
same two monitors if I ever want to show
a laptop I'll just plug it into the main
monitor
cut my PC over to a single screen and
then I can still use my PC on the
secondary monitor and I can just move my
mouse back and forth even across to my
laptop that's on the stand here
wow dang dude that's that's pretty sick
that I I've always wanted sort of like
that Synergy sort of setup to work you
know across multiple different computers
and having one Mouse but I I haven't
really ever gotten anything to work that
well so I'll have to check out Synergy
yeah Synergy is pretty solid I've been
using it for a number of years now I've
tried a couple other different pieces of
software I think there's an open source
version of it somewhere as well that's
like not terrible
um but yeah this this one has been
pretty much the best one that I've that
I've found and the most consistent in
terms of like performance and usability
and all that kind of stuff
so I I have in the notes as well you you
have a capture card don't you that you
use for some sort of what yeah what do
you do with that yeah so one I I bought
a capture card for like playing games or
something honestly the biggest advantage
that I found with it is that a capture
card is essentially a software display
right so if you download the capture
software and you have the capture card
plugged in it has an HDMI input that you
can use and normally it would you can
like record off of it or display it in
your stream or whatever you're going to
do with it but you can also just open
the software and you can display
whatever's going on the input so I'll
take a Raspberry Pi if I need to see
something on the display I'll plug it in
or if I need to debug something with it
with a temporary display I'll just plug
it into my my capture card and then I'll
just pull the software up and I don't
have to have like an extra monitor or
something that that I have lying around
that I use just for those things
yep that's
that's that right there that's my extra
monitor that I use plug in my Raspberry
Pi that's pretty sick dude actually I
especially for that specific you know
circumstance that you talked about where
you're trying to have the Raspberry Pi
displayed that that's something that
I've been like ah man I'd like
especially with the with the monitor
mounts that I've got I'm putting my hand
right in front of my my webcam here
especially with the monitor mounts that
I've got up like it's such a pain in the
ass to like get behind it and plug in
stuff and so uh you know I just I'm
using this other one of my other 40 you
know 4K uh monitors that I've got but I
think a capture card would be a really
nice addition and I actually think
because Mariah was doing streaming for a
while and and
um I think we've got one somewhere so I
ought to go see if I can track that down
and try to use it to do stuff like that
because that'd be really handy to have
it all in one spot yeah for sure
um keyboard and mouse uh I use a custom
keyboard
uh Joel I could feel it I knew you were
a keyboard junkie you're like I'm a
keyboard junkie hold on I'll give you a
little sound
[Music]
[Applause]
ah dude it's like it's like ASMR right
there like that uh yeah pretty good so
yeah it's called the Vega
um they're like impossible to get but I
have a friend who had one and I got it
for like crazy cheap so anybody who
knows keyboards will probably be like
losing their mind but yes I have a Vega
um it's all white and uh for my mouse I
use uh the uh the G Pro super lights
it's like
super super crazy lightweight
um the main reason I really like that is
because you like that yes the main thing
I like is that it has this little puck
here and uh this Puck is called um light
speed and essentially Logitech has a
software uh and I bought into this a
little while ago they have a mouse pad
that has like a a coil inside of it and
that coil communicates with uh with this
little puck here to charge your mouse
wirelessly through the mousepad so I
never ever plugged my mouse in it's
fully Wireless and it has sub one
millisecond response time because it was
made for gaming hitting me it uses like
a 2.4 gigahertz receiver and uh damn
Joey you have the coolest [__] man I
swear like yeah so I used to have like a
heavier like gaming I it was like a g903
or something I think I think is what it
was and that was pretty good for a while
but it had like extra buttons and and it
just was like heavier than I wanted and
I found out that the the super light has
support for the little charging puck and
I already had the the mouse pad and I
wanted to keep that because I don't like
plugging stuff in so yeah I've been
using that and that's been amazing it's
so funny like I for some reason
literally every time my mouse dies it's
I'm in a League of Legends game like
like without fail and I'm like in the
middle of a team you know Team Battle
and like all of a sudden it's like oh I
can't I can't move like help that's
terrible I saw it you had one of these
yeah so yeah so that's my this was my
main Mouse for a long time those of you
actually listening to our podcast it's
the uh Logitech MX Master 3 is the one I
use yeah so I've got the original this
is the first version but yeah I love my
MX Master as like a daily like Comfort
like
just daily driver Mouse if you don't
care about like lightweight Mouse and
any of that like wireless charging and
all that kind of stuff MX Master is such
a good such a good Mouse I have the MX
anywhere as well which is their like
mini MX Mouse for like travel and that
was also awesome
yeah dude I just I love the scroll bar
on this guy like oh yeah we can unlock
it's so yeah I really like spin it if
you really want to and then you can also
push on it and then it's got like a nice
click when you infinite scroll of mine
it's great I love it yeah it's it's real
good so I I really like this guy I I do
have an ergonomic Mouse as well one that
kind of is upright and you kind of hold
it like that I think it's called a
vertical Mouse yeah vertical Mouse and
it's like
pretty good but I actually haven't felt
any wrist issues yeah I say that into my
wrist like I don't know if you can hear
it's cracking it's like it's like
cracking like crazy
um but you know man this is kind of
enlightening actually maybe I should uh
but you know I could never really get
used to it and it's such a pain when
you're trying to like you know get do
your job and then you just got like a
bunch of needless friction you know
that's derailing your thought process so
I was just kind of reverted back to the
MX Master because it's it's really handy
yeah for sure for something like that I
think it's really just like what's your
personal preference the MX Masters handy
uh but I almost missed them oh God
you're welcome you know thank you I
thought you'd want to know on that okay
yeah okay yeah yeah so Adeline was
saying before I got dad joked out of
existence
um yeah mice are really it's really
personal preference it's up to you like
what feels comfortable so like I know
people who have like wrist problems and
they swear by those like vertical mice
or like the ergonomics or that kind of
stuff and um you know for me I just uh
if it feels good I don't think about it
too much and uh you know it is what it
is
um for sure okay so we're we're already
at the hour mark here
um wanted to cover a couple things so I
want to talk about we're going to
eliminate the rest of things on the list
here but I think we should talk about
our computer setup our chairs sure and
then
um what was the oh yeah I wanted to talk
about my my newest little Chromebook my
little Chromebook setup oh your
Chromebook oh cool cool yeah yeah so
actually I'll do that now it's right
here actually it's an Acer
what is it it's that guy right there
it's an Acer
r841t series
um and I think it's got like you know
like eight gigs of RAM or something like
that it was only like I want to say 600
bucks
um extremely lightweight you know two
pounds
um and uh you know it doesn't have a ton
of ram
um but you know it kind of gets the job
done and uh it's a 13 inch is it a 13
inch might be a might be an 11 inch so
some somewhere in that range I feel like
it's very portable you know and that's
kind of how I wanted to be able to to
you know to feel when I was using it I
wanted to be able to just throw it in my
little mini backpack my little Explorer
backpack that I've got and feel like
it's not even there and then pull it out
when I need it
um to just do some quick typing for
Content creation or even for hacking and
I brought it on a um on a trip with me
to Maine to summarize family and um and
it worked great for super lightweight
hacking you know like in the evenings we
were sitting around like watching a show
or something I was like you know maybe
I'll just fiddle around with something
and I powered up zero tier
um for your recommendation connected
back to my home network and I had uh you
know a kaido instance running on my my
pc at home nice and I used a zero tier
um and you know kaido's remote sort of
feature to connect into that I could
proxy all my traffic through it and it
was really really nice it worked really
well and I could do all of my all of my
sort of basic testing that I want to do
you know at a basic level nothing crazy
um you know from the from the Chromebook
and I didn't have to Lug around my big
you know eight pound laptop that I
normally have to use to use burp yeah
that's crazy are you running anything
like custom on it or is it just the
stock OS
well um Chromebook added support for
Linux so um you can you literally you
just kind of go in there and just like
turn on Linux and then you've got like a
Linux command line it's they still don't
have like key key bindings which is kind
of crazy to me so I couldn't like I
couldn't I normally like to hit like you
know I have my open a terminal bound to
like Windows key enter on my main
computer right and so I can just boom
and I'm in the terminal you know Bam Bam
Bam and uh and it takes like two or
three
I guess keystrokes on the on the device
to get it to open up the terminal but
once it's in it's pretty much like WSL
you know it's it's running a little
internal a Docker container that runs
Linux and and it's pretty pretty
functional
um and I was actually even I was just
kind of playing around with it I was
able to install kaido on the device
itself actually yeah I was going to ask
you did you just proxy directly to your
kaido IP at home or like what did you I
I proxied through my kaido IP at home
primarily but I also at one point um
installed kaido on the device and
started using it there but it got a
little overrun um even with kaido you
know being as efficient as it is
um it got a little overrun with that so
I reverted back to the you know the
setup from before of just kind of having
it open as a tab in my browser cool cool
that's awesome yeah I've always I've
always thought about doing like a
Chromebook I'm running an old Intel 2018
MacBook but my my work laptop is an M1
and um I think for my next my next
laptop I'll probably go with the Apple
silicon either either I'm actually
thinking about maybe a MacBook Air
because the MacBook Air stats first of
all they're way cheaper but also they
have an M2 and the new Macbook Air and
it's started
yeah like the cheap one the M1 13-inch
starts at a thousand bucks starts at
9.99 and then like even the 15 inch
brand new M2 starts at like 1200 1300 so
wow that's not bad it's not like that
bad because the price is so much lower
with the Apple silicon and those chips
are insane they're like they're
workhorses they use like no battery
they're crazy crazy quick
um I have basically no complaints except
for some of the very very like Edge case
weird x86 64 emulation stuff that comes
with Rosetta 2 uh but you can you can
look up that stuff if you're curious
about that yeah no I I was kind of so I
held off on buying the setup for a while
because it was like ah I really kind of
want to wait well first of all like I'm
pretty anti-apple to be perfectly honest
and it's not necessarily founded like I
feel like there are a lot of
you know respected hackers and
technologists you know yourself included
that use apple as their primary you know
system and that's that's fine it's just
not for me like I just I just I don't
like the feel you know The Branding it
just I don't know so I've been I've been
kind of waiting for people to come out
with a competitor to the M1 because I
love the idea of you know you know using
a system like that you know so efficient
and so you know battery uh efficient
[Music]
um
but they're just not doing it you know
and it's just not happening and you know
Apple's already releasing M2 and and you
know there's not even a competitor to
the M1 out there yeah and I'm like come
on guys like get it together so anyway
at some point I was just like you know
it's great it's 600 bucks I'm not gonna
like you know yeah it's definitely worth
it to have something light and portable
with me all the time and reduce that
friction to you know simple hacking and
content creation so I I went ahead and
bought it but I'm definitely going to
keep my eye out for you know an
arm-based uh you know PC that will come
out in the in the near future yeah for
sure cool
um all right let's talk about chairs
real quick this is uh I mean this one's
super easy I think chairs I see you have
a DX racer I don't know what your idea
is on that but but uh my take is Herman
Miller or bus
um I had an air on for probably about
seven years and then I switched over to
uh Herman Miller in body uh which is
like yeah a better I guess in my opinion
better version that's got better back
support and stuff
um also by Herman Miller and that uh
I've been on that one for maybe six
months now and uh yeah that one's also
awesome I I used it uh when I used to
work in the office
um at my last job and so I got one for
home finally
nice dude yeah I um I bought this
dxracer like when I graduated college so
I haven't I haven't you know changed at
all since I since I bought it but
um to be honest I mean it does the job
for me it it's adjustable you know
um the the neck support and back support
is pretty lower back support is pretty
good uh it's not as adjustable as it
could be but you know it's pretty good
um and it's something that I haven't I
haven't spent a lot of time
um optimizing but I think at some point
I will go ahead and and buy Herman
Miller because everyone you know Raves
about them
um and but like I said you know I don't
actually feel a lot of aches and pains
from sitting and I I saw a quote
recently that that was from a respected
you know posture physician of sorts you
know uh and they were saying that the
the best posture for you to have is one
that changes every 15 minutes
essentially you know like as long as
you're not leaning you know if you've
got your foot up on your desk and you're
like you know head crank to the side
that's fine for 10 minutes you know and
then you kind of got to move
um so as long as you're not staying
stagnant in one position for you know a
long time it's it's not too big of a
deal I don't think um plus I use the
standing desk feature of of my of my
desk on a pretty regular basis so
um I think the the chair is a really
good investment for most people that
spend a lot of time there
um for me it's a little bit lower on the
punching list yeah for sure I um based
on what I've read those those racing
chairs are like the worst for your back
but but yeah your mileage may vary like
some people have just like you know
either they change their their position
a lot or or it doesn't you know bother
them because they have a strong back or
whatever whatever it is so you know
whatever works for you if you want some
good chair reviews there's a YouTube
channel that I really like
um it's honestly
a-h-n-e-s-t-l-y well
honestly yeah like Ahn yes Ahn yeah
e-s-t-l-y yeah and uh honestly that's
kind of interesting yeah interesting
spelling on on honestly but yeah no he
uh he does like
that like chair reviews but like videos
and it goes like very in-depth he
Compares them to like other high-end
chairs and all that kind of stuff he'll
talk about like the drawback so it's
like you know if you're looking at
getting a chair what a niche nice chairs
are expensive you know it's like fifteen
hundred two thousand dollars for for a
nice chair and it's an investment that
you're gonna be sitting in for many many
years so I would recommend
um do some research on it I bought
actually during the pandemic I bought a
chair and I used it for like six months
and I hated it so much that I went back
to my old chair my oldest I switched
from an Aeron to like an office Master
something something or other it was like
500 bucks and I was like oh this would
be great it's got a headrest and all
this stuff and I use it for six months
and it was like creaking and it was like
hard to use and it wasn't comfortable
and I was like screw this and I went
back to my air on and I used that for
another like two years before I got my
body
nice dude yeah it's so funny to me all
these little niches that are all over
the place man this guy honestly has like
52k subscribers and that's just chairs
it's just chairs it's just like he's the
chair guy you know he's the chair guy
it's crazy that's hilarious all right
man that's uh that's a wrap on what we
had in the dock you got anything else
before we bounce no I don't think so
that I could I could rant on and on
about why I bought what I bought so we
should probably end it before yeah we're
gonna cut it
that's great all right man well good
luck in the uh in the live hacking event
this week and yeah I'll catch you next
time yeah you too catch you later all
right peace peace
what's up y'all got some quick
announcements for us at the end of the
podcast here
um one and hamcon is going on this week
so if you haven't signed up for that
head over to nahamacan.com and don't
miss out on that awesome uh the awesome
talks that are going to be given
um it's definitely going to be a banger
this year so definitely watch that uh
also our producer here at critical
thinking Richie Mills has launched his
new Audio Drama and I'm not gonna lie I
binge listened to the whole thing in the
first day that it came out and it is
real good so if you enjoy sci-fi fantasy
uh give homicide at Heaven's Gate a
search and we'll drop it in the
description below as well
um definitely definitely recommend uh
also I wanted to announce as I did last
week re-announce that Jesse Rivera has
joined the Christmas King podcast team
um he'll be doing the blog cast from now
on
um so if you head over to
criticalthinkingpodcast.io and drop your
email you'll always be up to date on the
awesome newsletters and text-based
content he'll be putting out that's all
for today see you next week
foreign